export const CHEMISTRYA2020 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. Which of the following substances is an example of a fine chemical?",
A: "Sodium hydroxide",
B: "Hydrochloric acid",
C: "Ethylene",
D: "Ammonia",
answer: "B. Hydrochloric acid",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. The IUPAC name of the compound represented by the structure below is ?",
A: "2- chloro but-I ,3-diene.",
B: "But-1,3-chlorodiene.",
C: "2-chloro but-diene.",
D: "3 -chloro but -1.3-diene.",
answer: "A. 2- chloro but-I ,3-diene.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. Which or the following substances is a polypeptide?",
A: "Starch",
B: "Glycogen",
C: "Protein",
D: "Fats",
answer: "C. Protein",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. Which or the following products could be formed during incomplete combustion of a hydrocarbon. \nI.Carbon  \nII. Hydrogen \nIII. Carbon (II) oxide",
A: "I only",
B: "I and II only",
C: "I and III only",
D: "II and III only",
answer: "C. I and III only",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. What quantity of electrons is lost when one mole of iron (II) ions is oxidized to iron (III) ?",
A: "0 mole",
B: "3 moles",
C: "1 mole",
D: "2 moles",
answer: "C. 1mole",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. What is the mass of silver deposited when 24,125 C of electricity is passed through a solution or silver salt. [Ag = 108, IF = 96,500 C ]",
A: "432g",
B: "108g",
C: "54g",
D: "27g",
answer: "D. 27g",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. Equal masses of calcium trioxocarbonate(iv) were added to dilute hydrochloric acid at the temperature specified. Under which of the following conditions would the reaction be slowest?",
A: "Calcium trioxocarbonate ( iv ) chips a 20°C",
B: "CalcIum trioxocarbonate (IV) chips at 40°C",
C: "Calcium trioxocarbonate (IV) powder at 20°C",
D: "Calcium trioxocarbonate (IV) powder at 40°C",
answer: "A. Calcium trioxocarbonate ( iv ) chips a 20°C",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. The high solubility of ethanol in water is due to?",
A: "its low boiling point.",
B: "its low freezing point.",
C: "its covalent nature",
D: "hydrogen bond",
answer: "D. hydrogen bonding",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Which of the following metals reacts slowly with cold water?",
A: "Calcium",
B: "Silver",
C: "Iron",
D: "Potassium",
answer: "D. First ionization energy and melting point",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. Which of the following pairs of properties of alkali metals decreases down the group?",
A: "First ionization energy and reactivity",
B: "melting point and atomic radius",
C: "Reactivity and electronegativity",
D: "First ionization energy and melting point",
answer: "A. Calcium",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. The most suitable process of obtaining water from an aqueous solution of sugar is",
A: "Crystallization",
B: "Distillation",
C: "Filtration",
D: "Decantation",
answer: "A. Crystallization",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. Group VIl elements in their combined states are called?",
A: "Halogens",
B: "Anions",
C: "Halide",
D: "Cations",
answer: "A. Halogens",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. When an ionic bond is broken, bonding electrons are",
A: "shared between participating atoms",
B: "gained by the most electropositive atom",
C: "gained by the most electronegative atom",
D: "lost by both participating atoom",
answer: "B. gained by the most electropositive atom",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. The oxidation state of chlorine in NaClO3 is?",
A: "+1",
B: "+3",
C: "+5",
D: "+6",
answer: "C. +5",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. A balanced chemical equation is based on the law of?",
A: "Periodicity",
B: "Constant composition",
C: "Multiple proportion",
D: "Conservation of mass",
answer: "D. Conservation of mass",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. Which of the following pairs of elements has the greatest difference in electronegativity?",
A: "Na and F",
B: "Na and CI",
C: "Na and Br",
D: "Na and I",
answer: "A. Na and F",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. A factor that is considered most important when siting a chemical industry is?",
A: "nearness to other industrial establishments",
B: "nearness to raw materials",
C: "favourable climate conditions",
D: "availability of storage facilities",
answer: "B. nearness to raw materials",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. The boiling point of pentane is higher than that of propane because?",
A: "carbon-carbon single bonds are stronger than carbon-hydrogen bonds.",
B: "Pentane has more covalent bonds to break",
C: "Pentane does not burn easily as propane",
D: "The intermolecular forces in pentane are stronger than those of propane",
answer: "B. Pentane has more covalent bonds to break",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. Which of the following solids would not decompose on heating?",
A: "Ammonium chloride",
B: "Lead (i) trioxonitrate (V)",
C: "Potassium trioxocarbonate (IV)",
D: "Sodium hydrogen trioxocarbonate (IV)",
answer: "C. Potassium trioxocarbonate (IV)",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. The following molecules have double covalent bonds between two atoms except?",
A: "oxygen",
B: "carbon (IV)oxide",
C: "ethene",
D: "water",
answer: "D. water",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. The type of isomerism exhibited by cis and trans isomers is?",
A: "positional",
B: "geometrical",
C: "functional",
D: "optical",
answer: "B. geometrical",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Which of the following compounds has the lowest boiling point?",
A: "C4H10",
B: "CH3COOH",
C: "H2O",
D: "C2H5OH",
answer: "D. C2H5OH",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. An alkanol containing 60% carbon by mass would have a molecular formula [H=1.0. C-12.0, O= 16.0]",
A: "CH3OH",
B: "C2H",
C: "C3H7OH",
D: "C4H9OH",
answer: "C. C3H7OH",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. Which of the following compounds would release hydrogen when reacted with sodium metal?  \nI. CH3COOH \nII. CH3CH2OH \nIII. CH3COOCH3",
A: "I only",
B: "I and II only",
C: "Il and IIl only",
D: "I and Ill only",
answer: "B. I and II only",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. Which of the following substances is not a reducing agent?",
A: "C",
B: "CO",
C: "O2",
D: "H2",
answer: "C. O2",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. Which of the following statements is correct for a reaction at equilibrium?",
A: "All reactions cease to occur",
B: "The reaction has gone to completion",
C: "The rates of the forward and backward reactions are equal",
D: "The amount of product equals the amount of reactants",
answer: "C. The rates of the forward and backward reactions are equal",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. Which of the following reactions are always exothermic? 1. Neutralization Il. Decomposition III. Combustion",
A: "I and II only",
B: "I and III only",
C: "II and IIl only",
D: "I, II and III",
answer: "B. I and III only",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. Which of the following standard conditions is not correct about energy changes?",
A: "Standard temperature is 298K",
B: "B. Standard pressure is 1 atm",
C: "Concentration of solution must be 1 mol/dm3",
D: "ΔH at 298 K is the activation energy",
answer: "D. ΔH at 298 K is the activation energy",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. If 5.0 cm−3 of 0.200 mol dm-3 Na2CO3 was diluted to 250cm-3 solution, what would be the concentration of the resulting solution?",
A: "0.004 mol dm-3",
B: "0.020 mol dm-3",
C: "0.200 mol dm-3",
D: "0.400 mol dm-3",
answer: "A. 0.004 mol dm-3",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. The initial volume and pressure of a given mass of gas is V and 3P. What is its pressure if its volume is increased to  2V at constant temperature?",
A: "3 P",
B: "2P",
C: "3/2 P",
D: "2/3 P",
answer: "C. 3/2 P",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. What volume of oxygen at s.t.p is required to burn completely 7.5 dm3 of methane according to the following equation? CH4 g + 202 g  → CO2 g + H2Og",
A: "3.75 dm3",
B: "7.59 dm3",
C: "15.0 dm3",
D: "30.0dm3",
answer: "C. 15.0 dm3",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. When 250 cm3 of a saturated solution of CuSO4 at 30°C was evaporated to dryness, 5.0 g of the salt was obtained.. What is the solubility of the salt at 30°C? [CuSO4 = 160",
A: "0.031",
B: "0.125",
C: "0.640",
D: "1.560",
answer: "B. 0.125",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. The bond between NH3 and H+ in NH4+ is?",
A: "dative",
B: "covalent",
C: "hydrogen",
D: "electrovalent",
answer: "A. dative",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Which of the following oxides has a giant covalent structure?",
A: "Al2O3",
B: "Na2O",
C: "P4O10",
D: "SiO2",
answer: "D. SiO2",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Which of the following hydroxides is not readily soluble in water?",
A: "NH4OH",
B: "Ca(OH)2",
C: "NaOH",
D: "KOH",
answer: "B. Ca(OH)2",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. Which of the following statements about the solubility of a salt is correct?",
A: "A salt whose solubility increases with temperature would not crystallize easily on cooling",
B: "A salt whose solubility is independent of temperature would normally crystallize out on cooling",
C: "Crystallization would be efficient in separating out a salt whose solubility increases considerably with temperature",
D: "Solubility of a solid does not affect its crystallization",
answer: "C. Crystallization would be efficient in separating out a salt whose solubility increases considerably with temperature",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. How many moles of H2SO4 are there in 50 cm3 of 0.108 mol dm3 solution of the ac",
A: "5.4x 10",
B: "5.4 x 10−3",
C: "5.4x 10−1",
D: "5.4 x 10−2",
answer: "B. 5.4 x 10−3",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. If 20 cm3 of sodium hydroxide was neutralized by 20 cm3 of 0.01 mol dm3 tetraoxosulphate(VI) acid, what is the concentration of the solution?",
A: "0.010",
B: "0.020",
C: "0.100",
D: "0.150",
answer: "B. 0.020",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. 'Electrons always occupy the lowest empty energy level' is a statement of",
A: "Aufbau Principle",
B: "Hund's rule",
C: "Pauli Exclusion Principle",
D: "Periodic law",
answer: "A. Aufbau Principle",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. Which of the following metals does not react with water to produce hydrogen?",
A: "Copper",
B: "Potassium",
C: "Sodium",
D: "Zinc",
answer: "A. Copper",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. Which of the following arrangement of elements is in decreasing order of electronegativity?",
A: "Na, Mg, Al, Si, P",
B: "Na, A1, Mg, P, Si",
C: "P, Mg, Na, Si, Al",
D: "P, Si, Al, Mg, Na",
answer: "D. P, Si, Al, Mg, Na",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. The metallic bond in magnesium is stronger than that in calcium because magnesium has a",
A: "larger atomic size.",
B: "smaller atomic size",
C: "greater number of valence electrons",
D: "lower melting point",
answer: "B. smaller atomic size",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. Consider the reaction represented by the following equation: AgNO3 + NaCl → AgCl + NaNO3. The steps that could be taken to obtain pure dry sample of AgCI (s) from the mixture includes",
A: "heating to saturation and drying",
B: "filtering and evaporation to dryness",
C: "filtering, washing and drying",
D: "crystallizing and allowing to cool",
answer: "C. filtering, washing and drying",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. How many electrons does  3115P3− contain?",
A: "12",
B: "15",
C: "16",
D: "18",
answer: "D. 18",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. The atomic number of an atom would be equal to its mass number if it",
A: "has a totally filled valence shell",
B: "has a high charge to mass ratio",
C: "does not contain neutrons",
D: "exhibits isotopy",
answer: "C. does not contain neutrons",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. Which of the following processes is not exhibited by atoms in order to attain more stable electron configuration?",
A: "Gaining of electrons",
B: "Hybridization of orbitals",
C: "Losing electrons",
D: "Sharing electron",
answer: "B. Hybridization of orbitals",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. which of the following quantities is a molar quantity?",
A: "Molarity",
B: "Molar mass",
C: "Mass concentration",
D: "Molality",
answer: "C. Mass concentration",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. Dilution factor is the?",
A: "amount of distilled water that is added to the concentrated solution to dilute it",
B: "Quantity of distilled water added to l dm3 of the concentrated solution to give the dilute solution",
C: "number of times the volume of the concentrated solution is diluted to give the dilute solution",
D: "act of diluting the concentrated solution to obtain the dilute solution",
answer: "C. number of times the volume of the concentrated solution is diluted to give the dilute solution",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. Calcium chloride is an ionic compound. Which of the following statements account for its ionic character? \nI.   Calcium has high ionization energy.   \nII. Calcium has low ionization energy.  \nIII. Chlorine has high electron affinity.  \nIV. Chlorine has high Ionization energy.",
A: "I and Il only",
B: "I, II and IV only",
C: "II, IIl and IV only",
D: "I, II, III and IV",
answer: "C. II, IIl and IV only",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. An example of a biodegradable pollutant is?",
A: "plastic",
B: "sewage",
C: "carbon (II) oxide",
D: "hydrogen sulphid",
answer: "B. sewage",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},


]